爸爸
Baba...
怎么了 儿子
Yes, my son.
给我讲个故事
Tell me a story.
哪个故事
Which one?
家乡的故事
The story of home.
数百万年前
Millions of years ago...
一颗振金陨星
A meteorite made of vibranium...
那是全宇宙最强大的物质
The strongest substance in the universe...
落在了非洲大陆上
Struck the continent of Africa...
它改变了附近的植物
Affecting the plant life around it.
当人类时代到来
And when the time of man came...
五个部落定居于此 并称之为瓦坎达
Five tribes settled on it and called it Wakanda.
几个部落总在彼此争斗
The tribes lived in constant war with each other...
直到一位萨满战士
Until a warrior shaman...
通过黑豹女神芭丝特看到幻象
Received a vision from the panther goddess bast...
并在她的指引下找到心形草
Who led him to the heart-shaped herb...
那株植物赋予了他
A plant that granted him
超人的力量 速度和直觉
superhuman strength, speed and instincts.
那名战士成为了国王
The warrior became king...
也是第一代黑豹
And the first black panther...
瓦坎达的保护者
The protector of Wakanda.
四个部落同意听从国王的统治
Four tribes agreed to live under the king's rule...
但贾巴里部落却自己隐于山中
But the Jabari tribe isolated themselves in the mountains.
瓦坎达人用振金发展了科技
The Wakandans used vibranium to develop technology...
先进程度超过其他任何国家
More advanced than any other nation.
但瓦坎达兴盛时
But as Wakanda thrived...
它周边的世界却进一步陷入混乱
The world around it descended further into chaos.
为了保护振金
To keep vibranium safe...
瓦坎达人决意隐藏起来
The Wakandans vowed to hide in plain sight...
对外界世界隐瞒
Keeping the truth of their power
他们真实的力量
from the outside world.
我们还在隐藏吗 爸爸
And we still hide, Baba?
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.tv
奥 克 兰
加 利 福 尼 亚
影片压制：无尽　调校：无尽　招募Q号：324446465
- 走运罢了 - 才不是
- Lucky shot! - That aingt lucky!
随便吧 走开
Whatever! Get outta here!
看着
Check up.
进攻啊 他没人守
Pick your man up! He open.
看哪呢
Where you at?
快点的
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
传球
Pass! Pass!
- 给你 - 快点
- Got you, es. - Es, hurry up!
瞧我的
Watch me get this.
蒂姆·哈达威的范儿 是吧
Tim Hardaway style. That's what I call it, baby.
来
Come on.
亮亮本事
What you got?
你什么本事都没有
You aingt got nothing.
听着 如果我们快进快出 就不会有麻烦
Look, if we get in and out quick, won't be no worries.
你开车 从西侧进来
You in the van, come in through from the west.
绕过拐角
Come around the corner.
停在这里
Land right here.
我和双胞胎停在这里
Me and the twins are pulling up right here.
把这辆车留下 我们…
We're leaving this car behind, okay? We come this...
把东西藏好
Hide the straps.
喂 是警察吗
Yo, is it the feds?
不是
No.
俩活像超模的小妞
It's these two Grace Jones-looking chicks.
还握着矛
They're holding spears.
开门
Open it.
真的吗
You serious?
他们不会再敲第二次的
They won't knock again.
你是谁
Who are you?
尼乔布王子 阿祖里之子
Prince N'Jobu, son of Azzuri.
向我证明你是我们的一员
Prove to me you are one of us.
国王陛下
My king.
下去
Leave us.
这是詹姆斯
This is James.
我敢把性命交给他 让他留下
I trust him with my life. He stays...
希望你允许 特查卡国王
With your permission, king T'Chaka.
那如你所愿
As you wish.
起身
At ease.
过来 弟弟
Come, baby brother.
让我看看你过得好不好
Let me see how you are holding up.
你看上去很强壮
You look strong.
芭丝特保佑 我很健康
Glory to bast, I am in good health.
家乡如何
How is home?
不太好
Not so good.
弟弟
Baby brother.
我们遭遇了袭击
There has been an attack.
这个人
This man...
尤利西斯·克劳
Ulysses Klaue...
从我们这里偷走了0.25吨的振金
Stole a quarter ton of vibranium from us...
为了逃跑 还在边境引爆了炸弹
And triggered a bomb at the border to escape.
害死了很多人
Many lives were lost.
他很清楚我们把振金藏在了哪里
He knew where we hid the vibranium...
也知道该如何袭击
And how to strike.
他有内应
He had someone on the inside.
你来这里干什么
Why are you here?
因为我要你看着我的眼睛
Because I want you to look me in the eyes...
告诉我你为什么要背叛瓦坎达
And tell me why you betrayed Wakanda.
我没有那么做
I did no such thing.
告诉他你是谁
Tell him who you are.
祖厉 巴度之子
Zuri, son of Badu...
什么
What?
詹姆斯 你骗我
James. James, you lied to me?
下去吧
Leave him.
你本就是瓦坎达人
You were Wakandan this whole time?
- 你背叛了瓦坎达 - 你怎么能这样骗我
- You betrayed Wakanda! - How could you lie to me like...
退下
Stand down.
你以为你是唯一被派来的探子吗
Did you think that you were the only spy we sent here?
尼乔布王子
Prince N'Jobu...
你要马上回国
You will return home at once...
并面见议会
Where you will face the council...
向他们坦白你的罪行
And inform them of your crimes.
看球
Check up!
守好人
Guard your man, guard your man!
喂
Yo.
现 今
小国瓦坎达
"The tiny nation of Wakanda
正在哀悼他们的特查卡国王之死
is mourning the death of its monarch, king T'Chaka.
这位挚爱的领袖是众多死难者之一
The beloved ruler was one of many confirmed dead...
他们皆死于一周前的联合国恐袭
After a terrorist attack at the united nations a week ago.
嫌犯已被逮捕
The suspect has since been apprehended.
瓦坎达仍是全球最贫困的国家之一
Though it remains one of the poorest countries in the world...
山脉是它的天然壁垒
Fortified by mountain ranges...
热带雨林铸就了不可穿越的屏障
And an impenetrable rainforest...
该国不与外界进行国际贸易
Wakanda does not engage in international trade
也不接受援助
or accept aid.
继承王位的
The succession of the throne...
将是国王两个孩子中的长子
Is expected to fall to the oldest of the king's two children...
特查拉王子
Prince T'Challa.
王子
My prince...
我们接近他们了
Coming up on them now.
山 姆 比 萨 森 林
尼 日 利 亚
不必 奥克耶 我自己来就好
No need, Okoye. I can handle this alone.
我会尽快救娜吉雅出来
I will get Nakia out as quickly as possible.
你看到她时可别僵住了
Just don't freeze when you see her.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我才不会僵住
I never freeze.
怎么回事
What's going on?
车熄火了 还打不着
It's the car. It lost power. It won't start.
车打不着
The car no start.
怎么回事
What happened?
引擎熄火了
The engine failed.
我们的也是
Ours, too.
怎么了 队长
What is it, captain?
准备防御
Defense positions.
我们遇袭了吗
Are we under attack?
准备防御
Defense positions.
去那边
Get around to the side.
准备防御
Defense positions.
Defense positions!
别耍花招
No games.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
回复 回复
Come in. Come in.
那边 注意
Over there! Look back!
小心
Watch out!
特查拉 不要
T'Challa, no!
他还是个孩子
This one's just a boy.
他也是被绑架来的
He got kidnapped as well.
娜吉雅
Nakia...
我想…
I wanted...
我瞄着她呢 别动 不然我开枪了
I have her! Don't move! I will shoot!
我会打死她的
I will shoot her right now.
你僵住了
You froze.
你来干什么 你破坏了我的行动
Why are you here? You've ruined my mission.
我父亲死了 娜吉雅
My father is dead, Nakia.
我明天要加冕为王了
I will be crowned king tomorrow.
我希望你能到场
And I wish for you to be there.
回家去吧
Carry yourselves home now.
带上那男孩 送他回族人那里
And take the boy. Get him to his people.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们绝不能提起今天的事
You will speak nothing of this day.
好
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
娜吉雅姐妹
Sister Nakia...
王子陛下
My prince...
我们到家了
We are home.
瓦 坎 达
怎么看都不腻
This never gets old.
王后
Queen mother...
公主
Princess...
节哀顺变
My comfort for your loss.
谢谢 娜吉雅
Thank you, Nakia.
很高兴你又回到了我们身边
It is so good to have you back with us.
带她去河部落 为仪式做准备
Take her to the river province to prepare her for the ceremony.
是 将军
Yes, general.
他僵住了吧
Did he freeze?
就像车前灯下的羚羊
Like an antelope in headlights.
闹够了没
Are you finished?
我妹妹居然会
So surprised my little sister came
在大日子前来看我
to see me off before our big day.
想得美
You wish!
我是为电磁脉冲珠来的 我做了升级
I'm here for the emp beads. I've developed an update.
升级 不 这个挺好使的
Update? No. It worked perfectly.
我还要教你多少次
How many times do I have to teach you?
就算好使
Just because something works
也总还有改进的空间
doesn't mean that it cannot be improved.
你教我 你知道什么啊
You are teaching me? What do you know?
比你知道得多
More than you.
我等不及看你怎么升级
I can't wait to see what kind of update you make
你的礼服了
to your ceremonial outfit.
苏睿
Shuri!
抱歉 妈妈
Sorry, mother!
你今天感觉怎么样 妈妈
How are you feeling today, mama?
骄傲
Proud.
你父亲和我经常谈论这一天
Your father and I would talk about this day all the time.
他与我们同在
He is with us...
你该成为国王了
And it is your time to be king.
伦 敦
英    国
大不列颠博物馆
早上好
Good morning.
我能帮你什么吗
How can I help you?
我就是来看看这些文物
I was just checking out these artifacts.
他们说你是位专家
They tell me you're the expert.
可以这么说
You could say that.
它们真美
They're beautiful.
这个是哪来的
Where's this one from?
波波阿尚蒂部落
The bobo ashanti tribe...
在如今的加纳
Present day Ghana...
是19世纪的
19th century.
真的吗
For real?
那这个呢
What about this one?
那个贝宁伊多人的文物
That one's from the Edo people of Benin...
16世纪的
16th century.
再跟我说说这个
Now, tell me about this one.
也是贝宁的 7世纪
Also from Benin, seventh century.
弗拉部落吧
Fula tribe, I believe.
不对
Nah.
什么
I beg your pardon?
是贝宁的英军劫走的
It was taken by British soldiers in Benin
但它原本来自瓦坎达
but it's from Wakanda.
而且是用振金制造的
And it's made out of vibranium.
别担心 我会把它带走的
Don't trip. I'm gonna take it off your hands for you.
这些文物是不出售的
These items aren't for sale.
你以为你的祖先是怎么得到它们的
How do you think your ancestors got these?
你觉得他们是付了公道的价钱买下的吗
You think they paid a fair price?
还是他们夺走的 就像其他一切他们夺走的东西
Or did they take it, like they took everything else?
先生 我得请你离开了
Sir, I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
这么多的保安 从我走进来就一直盯着我
You got all this security in here watching me ever since I walked in.
但你却没注意自己喝下了什么东西
But you aingt checking for what you put in your body.
好了 哥们 走吧
All right, mate. Let's have it.
行了 你该走了
Come on, mate. Time.
她好像不太舒服
I think she might not be feeling too good.
救命啊 来人啊
Somebody get some help! Come here!
叫个医生 拜托 谁救救她
Call a doctor, please! Please, somebody, come help!
急需医疗救援
Medical emergency right away
前往西非展厅 速来
in the west African exhibit, please, right away.
小心
Look out.
请退后 谢谢
Step back, please. Step back. Thank you.
借过 医务人员 借过
Coming through over there. Medics coming through.
我去休息一下
I'm gonna take a break.
给她点空间 拜托
Let's give the lady some space, please.
退后 先生们
Step back, please, gents.
请退后
Step back, please.
过来
Hey, come here.
Come here. Come here.
没事
It's okay.
你可以走 但别告诉任何人 好吗
You can go, but just don't tell anyone, all right?
哥们 你怎么不直接打死他
Bro, why you aingt just shoot him right here?
因为让犯罪现场分散开一点会更好
Because it's better to leave the crime scene more spread out.
让我们显得业余
Makes us look like amateurs.
监控循环
好了
Now then,
看看你说得对不对吧
let's see if you know what you're talking about.
小试牛刀而已
That's just a taste.
- 你要发财了 - 你最好赶紧出手
- You're gonna be a rich boy. - You better sell that quick.
已经出手了
It's already sold!
不管你想做什么 瓦坎达人会找上门来的
Whatever you try, the Wakandans will probably show up.
那最好不过了
That'll make my day.
我可以一石二鸟
I can kill two birds with one stone.
你不是说那也是振金吧
You're not telling me that's vibranium, too?
不 我就是挺喜欢
Nah, I'm just feeling it.
前进
Onward!
我 祖厉
I, Zuri...
巴度之子
Son of Badu...
为你们请出
Give to you...
特查拉王子
Prince T'Challa...
黑豹
The black panther!
王子
The prince...
现在将被剥去
Will now have the strength of the black panther
黑豹的力量
Stripped away.
先祖保佑
Praise the ancestors.
仪式格斗的胜利
Victory in ritual combat
由投降或战死决定
Comes by yield or death.
如果有哪个部落要举荐战士
If any tribe wishes to put forth a warrior
现在
I now offer
你有登上王位的机会
a path to the throne.
商贸部落今日不挑战
The merchant tribe will not challenge today.
边境部落今日不挑战
The border tribe will not challenge today.
河部落今日不挑战
The river tribe will not challenge today.
矿部落今日不挑战
The mining tribe will not challenge today.
是否有王室血脉
Is there any member of a royal blood
想挑战王位
who wishes to challenge for the throne?
这件束身衣好不舒服
This corset is really uncomfortable...
我们能不能赶紧完事回家了
So could we all just wrap it up and go home?
妈妈
Mother!
- 那是贾巴里的人吗 - 对
- Are they Jabari? - Yes.
姆巴库 你来做什么
M'Baku, what are you doing here?
今天是挑战日
It's challenge day.
我们一直
We have watched...
在山里观察 倾听
And listened from the mountains!
我们厌恶地看着
We have watched with disgust
你们把科技发展
as your technological advancements
交给一个孩子
have been overseen by a child!
她还嘲笑我们的传统
Who scoffs at tradition!
现在 你们又想把国家
And now you want to hand the nation
交给这位王子
over to this prince...
他甚至不能保护自己的父亲
Who could not keep his own father safe.
我们不能允许
We will not have it.
I said, we will not have it, oh!
我 姆巴库
I, M'Baku...
贾巴里部落的领袖
Leader of the Jabari...
我接受你的挑战 姆巴库
I accept your challenge, M'Baku.
哈努曼保佑
Glory to hanuman.
贾巴里
Jabari!
女子皇家护卫队
Dora Milaje!
前进
Onward!
挑战开始
Let the challenge begin!
站起来
Stand up!
来啊
Come!
特查拉
T'Challa!
你的神呢
Where is your god now?
好
Yes!
没有神力
No powers.
没有爪子
No claws.
没有战服
No special suit, oh!
只是个不配做领袖的小子
Just a boy not fit to lead!
让他见识你的本事
Show him who you are!
我是特查拉王子
I am prince T'Challa...
特查卡国王之子
Son of king T'Chaka!
你可以的 特查拉
You can do this, T'Challa!
好
Yes!
加油
Come on!
投降 别逼我杀你
Yield! Don't make me kill you.
我宁可死
I would rather die!
特查拉
T'Challa!
你打得光荣
You have fought with honor!
投降吧 你的人还需要你
Now yield! Your people need you.
特查拉
T'Challa!
投降吧
Yield, man!
特查拉
T'Challa!
太好了
Yes! Yes!
现在有请
I now present to you...
特查拉国王
king T'Challa...
黑豹
The black panther.
祖厉
Zuri.
国王陛下
My king.
瓦坎达万岁
Wakanda forever!
让心形草
Allow the heart-shaped herb
恢复黑豹神力
to restore the powers of the black panther
并带你进入先祖之域
and take you to the ancestral plane.
特查卡
T'Chaka...
我们呼唤你
We call on you.
来见你儿子吧
Come here to your son.
先祖保佑
Praise the ancestors.
父亲
Father.
儿子
My son.
对不起
I'm sorry.
站起来
Stand up.
你是国王了
You are a king.
怎么了 儿子
What is wrong, my son?
我还没准备好
I am not ready.
你难道不是这辈子
Have you not prepared
都在为做国王做准备吗
to be king your whole life?
难道你没有一直在我身边
Have you not trained and studied,
学习训练吗
been by my side?
我指的不是这个
That is not what I am talking about.
我还没准备好与你分离
I am not ready to be without you.
没有让孩子准备好
A man who has not prepared his children
面对他死亡的人
for his own death
是个失败的父亲
has failed as a father.
我辜负过你吗
Have I ever failed you?
从没有过
Never.
告诉我怎样最能保护瓦坎达
Tell me how to best protect Wakanda.
我想做个好国王 爸爸
I want to be a great king, Baba.
就像您那样
Just like you.
你会面临困境
You're going to struggle.
所以你要让身边 有值得信赖的人
So you'll need to surround yourself with people you trust.
你是个好人 有善良的心
You're a good man with a good heart.
好人是很难当好国王的
And it's hard for a good man to be king.
呼吸
Breathe.
特查拉 呼吸
T'Challa, breathe.
呼吸
Breathe.
我见到他了
He was there.
我见到他了 我父亲
He was there. My father.
就一个
Just one?
回家吧 娜吉雅
Come home, Nakia .
我不回来了吗
I'm right here.
别再走了
Stay.
我是来支持你
I came to support you
并缅怀你父亲的
and to honor your father...
但我不能留下
But I can't stay.
我在外面世界里找到了自己的使命
It's just, I found my calling out there.
我见到了太多贫困的人 不能再视而不见
I've seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye.
我在这里开心不起来
I can't be happy here
因为我知道外面世界里还有一无所有的人
knowing that there's people out there who have nothing.
那你希望瓦坎达做点什么
What would you have Wakanda do about it?
分享我们的资源
Share what we have.
我们可以提供援助
We could provide aid
分享技术
and access to technology
庇护难民
and refuge to those who need it.
其他国家也这么做 我们能做得更好
Other countries do it, we could do it better.
我们跟其他国家不一样 娜吉雅
We are not like these other countries, Nakia .
如果世界得知了我们真正的样子
If the world found out what we truly are,
我们拥有什么
what we possess,
我们可能会失去现在的生活
we could lose our way of life.
瓦坎达有足够的力量帮助他人
Wakanda is strong enough to help others
并保护自己
and protect ourselves at the same time.
如果你不是这么固执 本可以当个好王后
If you were not so stubborn, you would make a great queen.
正因为我固执 我才能当个好王后
I would make a great queen because I am so stubborn.
- 承认了吧 - 如果我想当王后的话
- See, you admit it! - If that's what I wanted.
那是它吗
Is that him?
芭丝特保佑 它还在长吗
Glory to Bast, man. Is he still growing?
当然
Of course.
娜吉雅回来了
I see Nakia is back.
你们要再续前缘吗
You guys going to work it out?
特查拉
T'Challa...
怎么了
What's wrong?
娜吉雅觉得我们该多做一点
Nakia thinks we should be doing more.
怎么多做
More, like what?
援助他国 难民计划
Foreign aid, refugee programs.
你放难民进来
You let the refugees in...
他们只会带来他们的麻烦
They bring their problems with them.
到时瓦坎达就会像其他地方一样了
And then Wakanda is like everywhere else.
如果你要我和我的人
Now if you said you wanted me and my men,
去清扫外面的世界
to go out there and clean up the world,
那我愿意
then I'll be all for it.
但我们从不会向他国宣战
But waging war on other countries has never been our way.
你也收到了
You, too, huh?
芭丝特保佑 我们有麻烦了
Bast! We're in trouble.
国王陛下
My king.
亲爱的
My love.
你们绝对猜不到我们刚发现了谁
You will never guess who just popped up on our radar.
一件未能被认出的瓦坎达文物
A misidentified Wakandan artifact
昨日被从大不列颠博物馆盗走
was stolen yesterday from a British museum.
我们得知 尤利西斯·克劳
We have learned Ulysses Klaue
打算于明晚在韩国将振金
plans to sell the vibranium to an American buyer
出售给美国买家
in South Korea tomorrow night.
克劳已经潜逃近30年了
Klaue has escaped our pursuits for almost 30 years.
未能逮捕他 或许是我父亲最大的遗憾
Not capturing him is, perhaps, my father's greatest regret.
我想把克劳抓回来接受审判
I wish to bring Klaue back here to stand trial.
瓦坎达现在需要的不是一名战士
Wakanda does not need a warrior right now.
我们需要一名国王
We need a king.
我父母在他的袭击中丧生
My parents were killed when he attacked.
我每一天都深深铭记着
Not a day goes by when I do not think about
克劳让我们失去了什么
what Klaue took from us.
让我失去了什么
From me.
这个机会太好 不容错过
It's too great an opportunity to pass.
带我一起去吧
Take me with you.
我们可以联手拿下他
We'll take him down together, side by side.
我需要你留下保护边境
I need you here protecting the border.
那我请求你
Then I ask,
要么将他就地正法
you kill him where he stands,
要么把他带回来
or you bring him back to us.
我保证
You have my word.
我会带他回来的
I will bring him back.
我们将执行这项任务
We will proceed with the mission.
国王陛下
My king!
别闹了
Stop it. Stop it.
我已经为你送了辆车去釜山
I've already sent a car ahead to Busan for you.
你要带谁跟你去韩国
Who are you taking with you to Korea?
奥克耶
Okoye.
还有娜吉雅
And Nakia as well.
你确定带你前任去执行任务是个好主意吗
You sure it's a good idea to take your ex on a mission?
是的
Yes.
我们不会有事的
We'll be fine.
再说 如果需要支援 我们还能联系你
Besides, you'll be on call should we need backup.
太好了
Yes!
我有好东西给你看 哥哥
I have great things to show you, brother.
这是你要在韩国用的通讯设备
Here are your communication devices for Korea.
不限距连线
Unlimited range,
还配有音频监控系统
also equipped with audio surveillance system.
看这个
Check these out.
遥控灵珠
Remote access kimoyo beads.
升级过 可以直接与我的沙台连接
Updated to interface directly with my sand table.
这又是什么
And what are these?
真正的问题是 你穿的是啥玩意
The real question is what are those?
你怎么在我的实验室里露脚指头
Why do you have your toes out in my lab?
怎么 你不喜欢我的王室拖鞋吗
What, you don't like my royal sandals?
我第一天登基 想打扮复古点
I wanted to go old school for my first day.
长老们肯定可喜欢了
I bet the elders loved that.
穿上试试
Try them on.
全自动
Fully automated.
就像爸爸以前看的那些美国老电影
Like the old American movie Baba used to watch.
我还把它们做成了绝对吸音的
And I made them completely sound absorbent.
有意思
Interesting.
猜猜我怎么称呼它们
Guess what I call them.
潜行鞋[运动鞋]
Sneakers.
双关了…
Because you...
算了
Never mind.
如果你要去对付克劳
If you're going to take on Klaue,
你会需要设计部能拿出的最好作品
you'll need the best the design group has to offer.
A展品
Exhibit a.
- 我的设计 - 老技术
- My design. - Old tech.
- 老 - 可用 但老了
- Old? - Functional, but old.
有人冲我开枪诶
"Hey, people are shooting at me.
等等 我戴上头盔先
"Wait, let me put on my helmet."
别闹了
Enough.
看这个
Now, look at these.
你喜欢那个吗
Do you like that one?
挺诱人
Tempting.
但我不想引人注意
But the idea is to not be noticed.
这个
This one.
叫它启动
Now tell it to go on.
整套战服都在项链坠里
The entire suit sits within the teeth of the necklace.
打一下
Strike it.
随便打吗
Anywhere?
别那么用力啊 天才
Not that hard, genius!
你叫我打的 你又没说多使劲
You told me to strike it. You didn't say how hard.
我请你来我的实验室
I invite you to my lab,
你就乱踢乱打吗
and you just kick things around?
或许你该把它造结实点
Well, maybe you should make it a little stronger.
等等
Wait a minute.
纳米材料能吸收动能
The nanites absorb the kinetic energy,
并锁定它 以待重新分配
and hold it in place for redistribution.
不错啊
Very nice.
再打一下同一个地方
Strike it again in the same spot.
你在录像吗
You're recording?
为了日后研究
For research purposes.
把视频给我删了
Delete that footage.
釜山
韩   国
这边走
This way.
希望能速战速决
Bast willing, this will go quickly,
我也能拿掉脑袋上这荒唐的玩意
and I can get this ridiculous thing off my head.
挺好看的 前后甩甩
It looks nice. Just whip it back and forth.
什么 真丢人
What? It's a disgrace.
你好 索菲娅
Hello, Sophia.
见到你很高兴
Good to see you.
他俩是谁
Who are these two?
我肯尼亚的朋友
My friends from Kenya.
大金主 他们没问题的
Very deep pockets. They're good.
"没问题"的麻烦精
Good for trouble...
就像你那样吗
...like you?
谢谢
Thank you!
散开
Spread out.
买家八成已经到了
The buyer is likely already here.
外面那女人
The woman outside.
她说的"麻烦"什么意思
What trouble was she referring to?
我跟一些象牙贩子起了点争执
I got into a disagreement with some ivory traders.
闹得有点大
Made a bit of a mess.
那今晚还会有什么麻烦吗
And will there be any trouble tonight,
肯尼亚女继承人小姐
Ms. Kenyan heiress?
看情况了
Depends...
要看你能多快完成任务
On how quickly we finish the mission.
我们能专心点吗
Can we please focus?
谢谢
Thank you.
喂
Over here.
请来杯威士忌
One whiskey, please.
注意 美国人
Eyes up. Americans.
我看见三个
I count three.
五个
Five.
你怎么能没看到你身后那俩油亮的背头
How could you miss greased lightning there behind you?
六个
Six.
我看到了一位中情局的老朋友
Just spotted an old friend who works for the CIA.
这下情况复杂了
It just got a little more complicated.
罗斯特工
Agent Ross.
陛下
Your highness.
你是克劳的买家
You are buying from Klaue.
不管我做什么
What I'm doing or not doing,
都是代表美国政府
on behalf of the U.S. government
而且与你无关
is none of your concern.
不管你是想干什么
Now, whatever the hell you're up to,
帮帮忙 别来妨碍我
do me a favor, stay out of my way.
我把泽莫交给了你
I gave you Zemo.
而我不是替你保守了秘密
Didn't I keep it under wraps,
没让人知道一位第三世界国家的国王
that the king of a third world country
穿着一身防弹猫咪战服满街跑吗
runs around in a bulletproof cat suit?
我觉得我们扯平了
I'd say we were even.
你真得马上走了
You really need to leave, now.
克劳要跟我走
Klaue is leaving out that door with me.
我警告你了
You've been warned.
三 双骰
Three, craps.
你赢了
You won!
知道吗
You know what?
这个我就
I think I'll just take these,
暂时拿来
bring them over here
替他保管一下好了
and hold on for safekeeping.
注意 瓦坎达国王来了
Okay, heads up. The king of Wakanda is here.
不能让他带走克劳
He cannot leave with Klaue.
好吧
All right.
索科威亚袭击事件中的振金
Vibranium from the attack on Sokovia
被查到了一个
links back to a person
我没说我要来这儿
that I'm not actually saying
就是为了跟他交易
I'm here to make a deal with,
但这次交易不会被取消
but that deal will not be called off.
等事情告一段落
When the dust settles,
我们可以谈个交易
you and me can work something out.
我不是来交易的
I'm not here to make a deal.
克劳 带了八个人
Klaue, plus eight!
将军
General.
已就位 可以守住出口
In position to secure our exit.
振金呢
And the vibranium?
我还没看到
I don't see it yet.
这里不是不许带武器吗
I thought there were no weapons allowed in here.
按理说是的
There's not supposed to be.
有人可能不知道呢
Somebody did not get the memo.
绝对有武器
Definitely armed.
好有架势的随从
Well, that is quite the entourage.
你是要发新专了吗
You got a mix-tape coming out?
是啊 还真有
Oh, yeah. Yeah, actually, there is one.
如果你喜欢 我可以把链接发你
I'll send you the soundcloud link, if you like.
戴夫 你能把音乐链接发给他吗
Hey, Dave, can you get the link to the tape?
拜托 别逼我听你的曲子
Please, don't make me listen to your music.
我就是说 你带了好多人来
I just meant you got a lot of people with you.
你以为他们是为你准备的吗
You think they're for you?
别担心
Don't worry.
我可以自己跟你完成交易
I can do a deal with you all by myself,
多谢了
thank you very much.
又来了六个 这是陷阱
Six more. It's a setup.
你拿钻石来了吗
You got the diamonds?
好了 别捏了
Okay. That's enough.
- 我们得去拿下克劳 - 别妄动
- We need to move on Klaue. - Stand down.
不能引起枪战
We can't afford a shootout.
振金呢
Vibranium?
易碎
我本想买个高档的公文箱
I was going to buy a fancy suitcase.
但还是决定省省钱
But I thought I'd save myself some money.
再不动手就没机会了
It's now or never.
别妄动
Stand down!
我被发现了
I've been made.
瓦坎达人 他们来了
Wakandans! They're here!
- 快走 - 杀光他们
- Get outta here! - Kill 'em all!
快去拿钻石
Diamonds, quick!
杀人犯
Murderer!
知道吗
You know,
你跟你老子真像
you look just like your old man.
我撒钱雨了
I made it rain!
我们走吧 老大
Let's get out of here, boss!
太爽了 太爽了
That was awesome! That was awesome!
走吧 开车 快走
Let's go! Go, go, go, come on!
- 我们丢下他吗 - 他会追上来的
- Do we just leave him? - He'll catch up.
苏睿
Shuri!
太好了
Yes!
遥控驾驶系统已启动
Remote driving system activated.
等等 这是左驾还是右驾
Wait! Which side of the road is it?
看在芭丝特的分上 开吧
For Bast's sake! Just drive!
好啦 冷静点
Okay, calm down!
走咯
Let's go!
放点音乐 你当这是送葬啊
Put some music on. What do you think this is, a funeral?
哪辆是他
Which one is he in now?
分头走
Hey, split up!
- 他们想甩掉我们 - 我追右边那个
- They're trying to lose us. - I'll take the right.
我们追另两个 我看到条近路
We'll take the other two! I see a shortcut.
我们过不去的
We're not going to make it!
继续开
Keep going!
老哥
Brother!
那是什么
Hey, what was that?
别想了 你棒棒哒
Don't worry about it. You're doing great.
枪
Guns.
真原始
So primitive!
那是振金车 白痴
It's a vibranium car, you idiots!
子弹打不透的
The bullets won't penetrate!
你干什么
What are you doing?
开你的车
Just drive.
该死
Shit!
看你的战服
Look at your suit.
你挨了好多子弹
You've been taking bullets,
战服积蓄了不少动能
charging it up with kinetic energy.
绕到卡车另一边
Pull around the truck.
他哪去了
Where'd he go?
臭显摆
You show-off.
他在那里
There he is!
抓紧了
Hold tight!
好 我们玩玩吧
All right. Let's have some fun!
跳上来
Hop in.
把矛放后备箱里吧
Put that spear in the trunk.
再快点 苏睿
Faster, Shuri.
我已经开到最快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
右转 右转
Take a right! Take a right!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
老哥
Brother!
克劳
Klaue!
你以为我们会忘记吗
Did you think we would forget?
看着我 杀人犯
Look at me, murderer!
这武器你从哪弄来的
Where did you get this weapon?
你们这些野蛮人不配拥有它
You savages didn't deserve it.
饶命啊 陛下 饶命
Oh, mercy, king. Mercy.
你喘的每一口气都是我仁慈的体现
Every breath you take is mercy from me.
陛下
King!
世界在看着呢
The world watches.
来吧 几位 我们快走吧
Come on. Guys. Let's go, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
有人吗
Hello.
我看得到你们 真的
I can see you! I can. I can see you.
真是闹得好大
So this is a big mess, huh?
我们不如唱红脸白脸
I figured we could go good cop, bad cop.
我先进去跟他谈 然后你们去
I'll talk to him first, then you guys go in.
我们不能让他单独跟克劳谈
We can't let him talk to Klaue alone.
最好让他单独跟克劳谈5分钟
Better to let him talk to Klaue alone for 5 minutes
别在这里闹不愉快
than to make a scene here.
等你审问过他
After your questioning,
我们要带他回瓦坎达
we will take him back to Wakanda with us.
什么 不行
What? No.
我很喜欢你
Look, I like you, a lot.
但他已经被我缉拿 他哪里都不去
But he's in my custody now. He's not going anywhere.
听着 我光是允许你们来
Listen, I'm doing you guys a favor
就是给你们面子了
by letting you even be in here.
他再敢碰你一次
If he touches you again,
我就把他插在那个桌子上
I'm going to impale him to this desk.
她会说英语吗
Does she speak english?
她想说就说
When she wants to.
我进去了
I'm going in.
等我问完了 你们再上
When I'm done, you guys are up.
- 罗斯特工 - 怎么
- Agent Ross. - Yeah?
我很感谢你在釜山的帮助
I do appreciate your help in Busan.
瞧见没
You see that?
这叫外交
It's called diplomacy.
不客气
You're welcome.
奥克耶
Okoye.
客气点
Play nice.
美国人啊
Americans.
不要再伤害我
Don't hurt me no more
爱是什么
What is love?
宝贝 别再伤害我
Baby, don't hurt me
不要再伤害我
Don't hurt me no more
你不该相信那些瓦坎达人
You know, you really shouldn't trust the Wakandans.
我跟你才是一类人
I'm much more your speed.
我干这行 谁都不信任
I don't trust anybody, not in this job.
但我对外面那个手臂炮感兴趣
But what I am interested in is that arm cannon out there.
那是哪来的
Where'd you get that?
就是被我调试过的旧采矿工具
It's an old mining tool that I made some adjustments to.
但如果你要 我可以给你弄一个
But I can get you one, if you like.
你何不说出你供货商的名字
Why don't you give me the name of your supplier,
我直接去找他们要
and I'll ask them.
他就在外面
He's right outside.
你自己去问他好了
Why don't you ask him yourself?
什么 特查拉吗
What? T'Challa?
你是说你手臂上的武器是瓦坎达来的
You're telling me that weapon on your arm is from Wakanda?
对了
Bingo.
你对瓦坎达究竟有什么了解
What do you actually know about Wakanda?
牧羊 纺织 衣服很酷
Shepherds, textiles, cool outfits.
那都是幌子
It's all a front.
探索者找了那里几个世纪
Explorers searched for it for centuries.
传说中的黄金城
El dorado, the golden city.
他们以为是在南美洲
They thought they could find it in South America,
但其实本就是在非洲
but it was in Africa the whole time.
一个科技奇迹
A technological marvel.
就因为这个国家脚下
All because it was built
就是世上最珍惜的金属
on a mound of the most valuable metal known to man.
他们称之为"天赐"
Isipho, they call it. The gift.
就是振金
Vibranium.
振金 嗯 地球上最坚硬的金属
Vibranium, yeah, strongest metal on earth.
不仅仅是金属
It's not just a metal.
他们把它缝进衣服里
They sew it into their clothes.
用它为城市供能 开发科技
It powers their city, their tech,
制造武器
their weapons.
武器
Weapons?
是的
Yeah.
我的手臂炮相比之下就像吹叶机
Makes my arm cannon look like a leaf blower.
这真是个美丽的童话
That's a nice fairy tale,
但瓦坎达是个第三世界国家
but Wakanda is a third world country,
而且你把他们的振金都偷走了
and you stole all their vibranium.
我偷…
I stole...
我都偷走了
All of it?
我拿的不过九牛一毛
I took a tiny piece of it.
他们还有整整一山的
They have a mountain full of it.
他们已经开采了数千年
They've been mining it for thousands of years...
却还只是触及了矿藏的表层
And they still haven't scratched the surface.
我是唯一见到了真相
I'm the only outsider who's seen it
还活着出来的外人
and got out of there alive.
如果你不信
If you don't believe me,
你去问问你的朋友 他的战服是什么做的
you ask your friend what his suit is made of.
他的爪子是什么做的
What his claws are made of.
你父亲对联合国说
Your father told the UN
克劳盗走了你们全部的振金
that Klaue stole all the vibranium you had.
但现在他却说你们还有
But now he's telling me you have more.
你相信一个
And you believe the word
捆在椅子上的军火贩的话吗
of an arms dealer strapped to a chair?
这是哪里
Where is that?
后面
Back there.
你们还藏了多少
How much more are you hiding?
外面有情况
Something is happening out back.
趴下
Get down!
别动
Stand down!
找掩护
Cover!
手雷
Grenade!
你们还真是不紧不慢啊
I see you took your time, didn't you?
陛下
My king!
My king.
娜吉雅
Nakia.
他替我挡了子弹
He just jumped in front of me.
他在这里是治不好的
I don't think he'll make it here.
子弹击中了脊椎
It hit his spine.
给我一颗灵珠
Give me a kimoyo bead.
这能暂时稳定他的情况
This will stabilize him for now.
把他交给我们
Give him to us.
我们可以救他
We can save him.
我们的任务是抓克劳回去
Our mission was to bring back Klaue.
我们失败了
We failed.
此人还是外国情报人员
This man is a foreign intelligence operative.
我们要如何解释带他进入国境内
How do we justify bringing him into our borders?
他替我挡了子弹
He took a bullet for me.
那是他的选择
That was his choice.
那我们就要任由他死去吗
So now we are just supposed to let him die?
想想看 如果我们治好了他
Let us consider that we heal him.
他有责任向他的国家汇报情况
It is his duty to report back to his country.
作为国王 你则有责任保护我们国家
And as king, it is your duty to protect ours.
我很清楚我的职责 将军
I'm well aware of my duties, general.
我不能任他死去
I cannot just let him die,
而我们明明能救他
knowing we can save him.
我们究竟要带他去哪
Where exactly are we taking him?
好啊 又带来个受伤的白人让我们治
Great! Another broken white boy for us to fix.
这会很好玩的
This is going to be fun.
他不会有事的
He will live.
瓦卡比来了
W'Kabi is here.
怎么回事 兄弟 克劳呢
What's going on, brother? Where is Klaue?
他不在
He's not here.
他从我们掌心里溜走了
He slipped through our hands.
"溜走了"
"Slipped"?
你父亲掌权30年 什么都没做
For 30 years, your father was in power and did nothing.
我以为你会有所不同
With you, I thought it'd be different.
但看来还是那样
But it's more of the same.
我们走吧 老大
Let's get going, boss.
你总卖给中情局吗
You always sell to the CIA?
我卖给出价最高者
I sell to the highest bidder.
别担心 等我回了约翰内斯堡
But don't you worry. When I get back to Joburg,
避过了这阵风头
and I lay low for a bit,
我会让你俩拿到工钱的
I'll make sure both you guys get paid.
我才不担心钱的事呢
I aingt worried about the money, bro.
我知道你拿得出
I know you good for it.
回去的路上 把我们丢在瓦坎达就好
On our way back, just drop us off in Wakanda.
你可不想去那里 小子
You don't want to go there, boy.
我想去
Yeah, I do.
放下
Drop it!
否则你们雌雄大盗的组合 今天就解散
Or your little Bonnie and Clyde routine ends today.
马上放下枪
Put your gun down now!
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 对不起 埃里克 - 没事的
- Sorry, Erik. - It's gonna be okay.
你真想去瓦坎达
You really want to go to Wakanda?
他们都是野蛮人
They're savages.
他们就这么对我们这样的人
This is what they do to people like us.
我可不怕烙印
I aingt worried about no brand.
看这个
Check these out.
每个都代表我杀的一个人
Each one is for a kill.
你怎么伤害自己无所谓
You can scar yourself as much as you'd like.
在他们看来 你始终是个外人
To them, you'll just be an outsider.
你要是以为自己能走进去就是疯了
You're crazy to think that you can walk in there.
我还当你是个疯子美国人呢
To think I saw you as some crazy American.
下去
Leave us!
你的任务未能如愿
So your mission did not go as planned.
我叔叔尼乔布究竟发生了什么
What happened to my uncle N'Jobu?
我父亲说他失踪了
My father told me he disappeared.
今天有个男人
There was a man today,
戴了跟这枚一样的戒指
wearing a ring identical to this one.
那不可能
That is not possible.
他帮助了克劳逃脱 而且他戴了这枚戒指
He helped Klaue escape from us and he was wearing this ring!
我爷爷的戒指
My grandfather's ring!
别告诉我什么可能不可能
Do not tell me what is possible.
告诉我真相
Tell me the truth!
有些真相
Some truths...
太过沉重 特查拉
Are too much to bear, T'Challa.
那不是由你来决定
That is not your choice to make.
他究竟怎么了
What happened to him?
我向国王保证过不会说的
I promised the king to say nothing.
现在我是你的国王了
I'am your king now!
你叔叔接受了
Your uncle took...
去美国做战士的任务
A war dog assignment in America.
你父亲
Your father...
把我安插在了那里
Placed me there...
观察他
To observe...
而他并不知情
Unbeknownst to him.
你叔叔爱上了个美国女人
Your uncle fell in love with an American woman.
他们生了个孩子
They had a child.
他在那里看到的困苦
The hardships he saw there...
让他变得激进
Radicalized your uncle.
我袖手旁观了很久
I observed for as long as I could.
他们的领袖遭人暗杀
Their leaders have been assassinated.
他们的社区被毒品和武器淹没
Communities flooded with drugs and weapons.
他们遭受警察暴力 执法过度
They are overly policed and incarcerated.
在世界各地
All over the planet
我们的同胞饱受苦难
our people suffer because
就因为他们没有反抗的能力
they don't have the tools to fight back.
如果有了振金武器
With vibranium weapons,
他们可以推翻每一个国家
they could overthrow every country,
瓦坎达可以一统天下
and Wakanda could rule them all
好好治理
the right way.
他知道你父亲绝不会答应
He knew your father would not support this.
所以 你叔叔背叛了我们
So, your uncle betrayed us.
不
No!
他帮助克劳盗取了振金
He helped Klaue steal the vibranium.
不 不
No, no, no.
你要马上回国
You will return home at once...
并面见议会
Where you will face the council...
向他们坦白你的罪行
And inform them of your crimes.
他举起枪对准了我
He drew his weapon on me.
不
No!
你父亲杀了亲弟弟
Your father killed his own brother...
救了我的命
to save my life.
决不许说出去
Speak nothing of this.
那孩子呢
And the child?
我们丢下了他
We left him.
我们必须
We had to...
守住
maintain...
那个谎言
the lie.
这是什么
What is this?
只是一份薄礼
Just a little gift.
你是谁
Who are you?
好吧 我在哪
All right, where am l?
别那么吓我 殖民者
Don't scare me like that, colonizer!
什么 我叫埃弗雷特
What? My name is Everett.
我知道 埃弗雷特·罗斯
Yes, I know. Everett Ross...
前空军飞行员 现中情局特工
Former air force pilot and now CIA.
没错
Right.
好吧 这是瓦坎达吗
Okay, is this Wakanda?
不 是堪萨斯
No, it's Kansas.
韩国是多久之前了
How long ago was Korea?
昨天
Yesterday.
不可能
I don't think so.
枪伤不会魔法般地一夜恢复
Bullet wounds don't just magically heal overnight.
在这里可以
They do here.
但不是靠魔法 是靠科技
But not by magic, by technology.
什么都别碰 我哥哥很快就会回来
Don't touch anything. My brother will return soon.
这些火车
These train things...
是磁悬浮的吧
That's magnetic levitation, right?
当然了
Obviously.
当然了 但我从没见过这么高效的
Obviously, but I've never seen it this efficient.
那个灯板 是干什么的
The light panels, what are they?
- 声波稳定器 - 什么
- Sonic stabilizers. - Sonic what?
未加工的振金太过危险
In its raw form vibranium is too dangerous
不能高速运输
to be transported at that speed,
所以我发明了一种办法让它暂时失效
so I developed a way to temporarily deactivate it.
那些火车上是振金
There's vibranium on those trains?
我们周围到处是振金
There's vibranium all around us.
我就是靠这个治好了你
That's how I healed you.
特查拉呢
Where is T'Challa?
他的灵珠被关闭了
His kimoyo beads have been switched off.
我们又不是连体婴 奥克耶
Well, we are not joined at the hip, Okoye.
有个男人出现在了边境 自称杀了克劳
A man showed up at the border who claims to have killed Klaue.
什么
What?
瓦卡比此刻正在送他去王宫
W'Kabi is transporting him, as we speak, to the palace.
我们得找到你哥哥
We need to find your brother!
一个外人吗
An outsider?
不 是瓦坎达人
No, a Wakandan.
他不是瓦坎达人
He's not a Wakandan.
他是我们的人
He's one of ours.
他杀了亲弟弟
He killed his own brother...
还丢下了一个孩子
And left a child behind...
让他一无所有
with nothing.
什么样的国王
What kind of king...
什么样的人会做出这种事
What kind of man does that?
人无完人
No man is perfect.
你父亲也是
Not even your father.
他都没好好安葬他
He didn't even give him a proper burial.
我叔叔尼乔布背叛了我们 但我父亲
My uncle N'Jobu betrayed us, but my father...
他可能制造了更可怕的东西
He may have created something even worse.
看着我
Look at me.
你不能让你父亲的错误决定你的为人
You can't let your father's mistakes define who you are.
你才能决定你要做怎样的国王
You get to decide what kind of king you are going to be.
哥哥 你得马上回来
Brother, you need to get here now!
埃里克·斯蒂文斯
Erik Stevens.
19岁从安纳波利斯毕业
Graduated Annapolis age 19...
在麻省理工学院攻读硕士
MIT for grad school.
之后加入海豹突击队 去了阿富汗
Joined the SEALs and went straight to Afghanistan,
在那里杀人无数
where he wrapped up confirmed kills,
好像在打电子游戏
like it was a video game.
开始有了杀人魔头的称号
Started calling him killmonger.
他加入了一个联合特种作战司令部的秘密部队
He joined a JSOC ghost unit.
他们可不是闹着玩的
Now these guys are serious.
他们会隐藏起来
They will drop off the grid,
进行刺杀
so they can commit assassinations
颠覆政府
and take down governments.
他有透露过他的身份吗
Did he reveal anything about his identity?
他有战士纹身
He has a war dog tattoo,
但我们并无他的记录
but we have no record of him.
这人到底是不是瓦坎达人
Is this man Wakandan or not?
告诉我们究竟怎么回事
Tell us what is going on.
说吧
Speak.
我来到了你的领地
I'm standing in your house,
处决了一个 盗走你们振金 还杀了你们人的罪人
serving justice to a man who stole your vibranium and murdered your people.
这是你们国王没能做到的
Justice your king couldn't deliver.
我不管你是不是带来了克劳
I don't care that you brought Klaue.
我之所以没有就地杀了你
Only reason I don't kill you where you stand
是因为我知道你的身份
is because I know who you are.
你想怎么样
Now, what do you want?
我想要王位
I want the throne.
天呐
My goodness.
你们都安安稳稳地坐在这里
Y'all sitting up here comfortable.
感觉很不错吧
Must feel good.
全世界还有20亿跟我们一样黑皮肤的人
It's about two billion people all over the world that looks like us.
但他们的生活要艰辛得多
But their lives are a lot harder.
瓦坎达有解放他们所有人的工具
Wakanda has the tools to liberate 'em all.
什么工具呢
And what tools are those?
振金 你们的武器
Vibranium. Your weapons.
我们的武器绝不会用来向世界发动战争
Our weapons will not be used to wage war on the world.
我们不会去评判外人的行为
It is not our way to be judge, jury and executioner
并决定赏罚
for people who are not our own.
外人
Not your own?
但生命不是在这个大陆上诞生的吗
But didn't life start right here on this continent?
那么所有人不都该是你的同胞吗
So aingt all people your people?
我不是所有人的国王 我是瓦坎达的国王
Iam not king of all people. I am king of Wakanda.
我的职责就是
And it is my responsibility
保证人民的安全
to make sure our people are safe
并确保振金
and that vibranium
不会落入你这种人手中
does not fall into the hands of a person like you.
儿子
Son.
我们已听够了这骗子的话
We have entertained this charlatan for too long.
拒绝他的要求
Reject his request.
我还没提出要求呢
I aingt requesting nothing.
- 问问我是谁 - 你是埃里克·斯蒂文斯
- Ask who I am. - You're Erik Stevens.
美国秘密特工
An American black operative.
绰号"杀人魔头"的佣兵
A mercenary nicknamed Killmonger.
那就是你的身份
That's who you are.
那不是我的名字 公主
That's not my name, Princess.
问我吧 国王
Ask me, king.
不
No.
问我
Ask me.
带他走
Take him away.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫尼贾达卡 尼乔布王子的儿子
I am N'jadaka, son of prince N'Jobu.
尼乔布的儿子
Son of N'Jobu?
我看到我爸爸尸体上有豹爪印
I found my daddy with panther claws in his chest!
你才不是国王的儿子 你是杀人犯的儿子
You aingt the son of a king. You a son of a murderer.
你撒谎
You're lying!
- 撒谎 - 恐怕不是 太后陛下
- Lies! - I'm afraid not, queen mother.
什么
What?
尼乔布的后人
The descendent of N'Jobu.
伯母好啊
Hey, auntie.
我要行使我与生俱来的权利
I'm exercising my blood right
挑战国王的王位
to challenge for the mantles of king
和黑豹的身份
and black panther.
别这么做 特查拉
Do not do this, T'Challa.
作为尼乔布王子的儿子
As the son of prince N'Jobu,
他有权利这么做
he is within his rights.
他在这里没有任何权利
He has no rights here!
挑战要准备数周
The challenge will take weeks to prepare.
数周 没那个必要
Weeks? I don't need weeks.
我不需要全国都来 只要他来就行
The whole country aingt gotta be there. I just need him.
还要来个人给我解开镣铐
And somebody to get me outta these chains.
特查拉 你知道此事吗
T'Challa, what do you know of this?
我接受你的挑战
I accept your challenge.
他打不过特查拉的
He'll never beat T'Challa.
他就该第一次挑战时来
He should've just come to the first challenge
早点了事
and gotten it over with.
国王现在
The king will now have
将被剥去黑豹的力量
the strength of the black panther stripped away.
罗斯特工呢
Where is Agent Ross?
我把他关在办公室里了 他哪都去不了
I locked him in the office. He's not going anywhere.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
放下武器
Throw down your weapons,
我们可以换个方式解决此事
and we can handle this another way.
我这辈子都在为此刻做准备
I lived my entire life waiting for this moment.
我训练 撒谎 杀人
I trained, I lied, I killed,
就为了来到这里
just to get here.
我在美国杀人 在阿富汗杀人
I killed in America, Afghanistan,
在伊拉克杀人
Iraq.
我在这个大陆上
I took life from my own brothers and sisters
杀过我自己的同胞
right here on this continent.
这么多死亡
And all this death...
就是为了杀你
just so I could kill you.
挑战开始
Let the challenge begin.
投降吧
Yield!
振作起来 特查拉
Snap out of it, T'Challa!
起来啊
Come on, get up.
来啊
Come here.
这是为了我父亲
This is for my father.
埃里克
Erik!
- 祖厉 不 - 住手
- Zuri, no. - Stop!
- 祖厉 - 祖厉 别
- Zuri! - Zuri, don't!
是我导致了你父亲的死
I am the cause of your father's death.
不是他
Not him.
杀我吧
Take me.
你们俩我都要杀 詹姆斯叔叔
I'll take you both, uncle James.
不
No!
不 不
No! No!
祖厉 不要
Zuri, no!
不
No!
不 祖厉
No! No! Zuri!
祖厉
Zuri!
不 不
No! No!
这就是你们的国王吗
Is this your king?
黑豹
The black panther,
他还要带领你们进入未来
who's supposed to lead you into the future?
加油啊 哥哥
Come on, brother!
我们不能做点什么吗
Is there nothing that can be done?
就他吗
...him?
他要保护你们吗
He's supposed to protect you?
- 不 - 不
- No. - No!
不
No!
不 我才是你们的国王
Nah. I'm your king.
- 不 - 我们得走了
- No! No! - We have to go now!
王太后 我们得走了
Queen mother, let's go!
王太后和苏睿 她们安全吗
The queen mother and Shuri, they are safe?
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们得立刻去找她们
We should get to them immediately.
我不能去
I cannot.
- 什么 - 虽然我的心与你们同在
- What? - Though my heart is with you.
我们不能把这个国家交给一个
We cannot turn over our nation to a man
几小时前才到来的男人
who showed up here only hours ago.
他是王室血脉
He is of royal blood.
- 他杀了特查拉 - 那是仪式格斗
- He killed T'Challa! - In ritual combat.
那真的要紧吗
Does that really matter?
你是瓦坎达最伟大的战士
You are the greatest warrior Wakanda has.
帮我推翻他 别让他羽翼丰满起来
Help me overthrow him before he becomes too strong.
推翻
Overthrow?
娜吉雅
Nakia!
我不是个可以自由来去的探子
I'm not a spy who can come and go as they so choose!
我要忠于王位 不管坐在上面的是谁
I am loyal to that throne, no matter who sits upon it.
你忠于什么
What are you loyal to?
我爱他
I loved him.
我也爱我的国家
I loved my country, too.
那你就该效忠国家
Then you serve your country.
不 我要救我的国家
No. I save my country.
怎么了
What's wrong?
国王死了
The king is dead.
跟我来 除非你也想一起死
Come with me, unless you want to join him.
先是爸爸
First Baba.
现在又是我哥哥
And now my brother.
妈妈 我们都不能安葬他
Mama, we didn't even get to bury him.
- 是我 - 娜吉雅
- It's me. - Nakia.
这人是谁
Who is this man?
他是特查拉的朋友 他救了我一命
He's a friend of T'Challa's. He saved my life.
奥克耶呢
Where's Okoye?
她不来了
Okoye is not coming.
她和女子皇家护卫队要效忠新王
She and the dora Milaje will serve the new king.
在这里等着
Wait here.
我们的瓦坎达是怎么了
What has happened to our Wakanda?
让心形草
Allow the heart-shaped herb
赋予你黑豹的神力
to give you the powers of the black panther,
并带你进入先祖之域
and take you to the ancestral plane.
不是叫你别乱翻我的东西吗
What did I tell you about going into my things?
你找到了什么
What did you find?
你的家乡
Your home.
我给了你钥匙 就是希望你有一日能见到那里
I gave you a key hoping that you might see it someday.
对
Yes.
那里有世上最美的日落
The sunsets there are the most beautiful in the world.
但恐怕你还是不会受欢迎
But I fear you still may not be welcome.
为什么
Why?
他们会说你迷失了
They will say you are lost.
但我就在这里
But I'm right here.
不为我流泪吗
No tears for me?
人人都会死
Everybody dies.
这里的生活就是如此
It's just life around here.
看看我做了什么
Well, look at what I have done.
我早该带你回去的
I should've taken you back long ago.
结果 我们都被抛弃在了这里
Instead, we are both abandoned here.
或许你的家乡才迷失了
Well, maybe your home is the one that's lost.
所以他们才找不到我们
That's why they can't find us.
呼吸 呼吸 国王陛下 呼吸
Breathe! Breathe, my king, breathe.
呼吸 呼吸
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
那是心形草的效力
The heart-shaped herb did that?
- 这是全部的了吗 - 对
- This all of it? - Yes.
这样等再有下任国王时
So when it comes time for another king,
我们会有所准备
we will be ready.
下任国王
Another king?
全烧了吧
Yeah, go ahead and burn all that.
陛下 我们不能那么做
My king, we cannot do that.
这是我们的传统
It is our tradition...
我叫你做什么的话 我就不是闹着玩的
When I tell you to do something, I mean that shit.
全烧了
Burn it all!
在我们那里
You know, where I'm from...
黑人掀起革命时
when black folks started revolutions,
从来没有足够火力
they never had the firepower,
和资源去对抗压迫者
or the resources to fight their oppressors.
那时候瓦坎达在哪
Where was Wakanda?
到此为止了
Yeah, all that ends today.
我们在全球每个国家都有探子
We got spies embedded in every nation on earth.
都已就位
Already in place.
我知道殖民者怎么思考
I know how colonizers think.
我们就用他们的策略对付他们
So we're gonna use their own strategy against 'em.
我们要把振金武器送去给我们的战士
We're gonna send vibranium weapons out to our war dogs.
让他们把武器分给全世界的被压迫者
They'll arm oppressed people all over the world...
让他们能起义 杀死当权者
so they can finally rise up and kill those in power.
还有他们的孩子
And their children.
和其他与他们同流的人
And anyone else who takes their side.
该让他们知道我们真实的样子了
It's time they know the truth about us!
我们是战士
We're warriors!
世界要大翻盘 这次 我们要占据上风
The world's gonna start over, and this time, we're on top.
瓦坎达将成为日不落帝国
The sun will never set on the Wakandan empire.
瓦坎达能延续至今
Wakanda has survived for so long,
一直是只在绝对必要时动武
by fighting when only absolutely necessary.
瓦坎达过去的确是如此行事
Wakanda survived in the past this way, yes.
但世界在改变 将军
But the world is changing, general.
长老们 世界越来越小了
Elders, it is getting smaller.
外面的世界在追赶上来
The outside world is catching up.
很快 局面就会成为不去征服
And soon it will be the conquerors
便会被征服
or the conquered.
我宁可做前者
I'd rather be the former.
你们都听到命令了 我们开始吧
You heard your orders. Let's get to it.
我们要去哪
So where are we going again?
我们要带心形草去贾巴里部落
We're taking the heart-shaped herb to Jabaril and.
心形草 那是什么
Heart-shaped herb? What is that?
服用者能获得增强的能力
It gives whoever takes it heightened abilities.
所以特查拉才那么强壮
It's what made T'Challa so strong.
娜吉雅
Nakia.
这样不好
I don't like this.
心形草是我们的
The herb belongs to us.
给姆巴库 可能会造就更大的怪物
We may be creating a bigger monster with M'Baku.
娜吉雅 你该自己服下它
Nakia, you should take it yourself.
我是个探子 还没有军队
I am a spy with no army.
我绝无机会的
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我们去吧
We'll go.
天呐
Oh, boy.
该死
Oh, shit.
低头 保持冷静
Look down. Stay calm.
苏睿
Shuri.
低头
Look down.
我儿子
My son...
在仪式格斗中被杀
was murdered in ritual combat.
- 机会公平吗 - 是的 但是
- Were the odds fair? - Yes, but...
那就不是"被杀" 而是"被击败"
So it was less a murder than a defeat.
- 别戳我们的痛处 - 闭嘴
- Do not rub our noses in it! - Silence!
在这里 我才有权说话 小丫头
I make the pronouncements here, girl.
殿下 新王是个美国…
Look, uh, your highness, the new king is a U.S...
新王
The new king...
你不能说话
You cannot talk!
再多说一句
One more word,
我就拿你喂我的孩子
and I will feed you to my children.
我开玩笑的 我们吃素的
I'm kidding. We are vegetarians.
大猩猩姆巴库
Great gorilla M'Baku...
我们是为此而来
This is why we are here.
我们要把它献给你
To offer this to you.
一个外人坐在了王位上
An outsider sits on our throne.
只有你能帮我们阻止他
Only you can help us stop him.
跟我来
Come with me.
不可能
Impossible!
他还有气吗
Is he breathing?
他陷入了昏迷 生命垂危
He's in a coma. Barely clinging to life.
我们的一个渔人发现了他
One of our fishermen found him
漂到了河边
at the edge of the river border.
他把他带来给了我
He brought him to me.
你怎么把他放在雪里
Why do you have him in the snow?
这是唯一让他不会去见祖先的东西
It is the only thing keeping him from joining the ancestors.
我们得送他去我的实验室 我在那里能治好他
We need to get him to my lab. I can heal him there.
带他走吧 不出几秒他就会死
Take him. He'll be dead in seconds.
娜吉雅 心形草
Nakia, the herb.
我呼唤祖先
I call upon the ancestors.
我呼唤芭丝特
I call upon bast.
我跟我儿子 特查拉在一起
I am here with my son, T'Challa.
治好他
Heal him.
我们得把他埋起来 盖住他
We must bury him. Cover him. Cover him!
好
Okay.
先祖保佑
Praise the ancestors.
醒醒 特查拉
Wake up, T'Challa.
醒来吧
Wake up.
儿子
My son.
你该回家来
The time has come for you to come home...
跟我团聚了
And be reunited with me.
为什么
Why?
你为什么不带那男孩回家
Why didn't you bring the boy home?
为什么 爸爸
Why, Baba?
他
He...
他是我选择无视的真相
He was the truth I chose to omit.
你不该抛弃他
You were wrong to abandon him.
我选择了我的人民
I chose my people.
我选择了瓦坎达
I chose Wakanda.
我们的未来需要…
Our future depended...
你错了
You were wrong!
你们都错了
All of you were wrong!
对外面的世界袖手旁观
To turn your backs on the rest of the world!
我们因为害怕被发现
We let the fear of our discovery
而没有做正确的事
stop us from doing what is right!
再不能了
No more!
我不能留下陪你
I cannot stay here with you.
我不能安心地让他坐在王位上
I cannot rest while he sits on the throne.
他是我们制造出来的怪物
He is a monster of our own making.
我必须夺回王位 必须
I must take the mantle back. I must!
我必须纠正错误
I must right these wrongs.
你们有毯子吗
Do you have a blanket?
杀人魔头有军队的完全支持
Killmonger has the full support of our military.
而且
And
他还烧掉了心形草园
he burned the garden of the heart-shaped herb.
当然了
Of course he did.
那是他受的训练
That's what he was trained to do.
他的部队以前曾跟中情局合作
His unit used to work with the CIA
颠覆外国政权
to destabilize foreign countries.
他们总在权力交接时出手
They would always strike at transitions of power...
比如大选之年 或是国王死后
Like an election year, or the death of a monarch.
控制政府 军队
You get control of government, the military...
- 我们的资源 - 没错
- Our resources. - Right.
圣山
The great mound.
我们的振金 我的科技
Our vibranium, all of my designs.
他会把我们的武器送去全世界
He will send our weapons all over the world.
你必须带她们安全离开瓦坎达
You must get them out of Wakanda safely.
- 什么 - 那你呢
- What? - What about you?
挑战还要继续
The challenge will have to continue.
特查拉 我们不会离开瓦坎达
T'Challa, we will not leave Wakanda.
我有责任保护你们
It is my duty to keep you safe.
如果他拿到了我们的科技
If he gets control of our technology,
哪里都不会安全了
nowhere will be safe.
黑豹不死
The black panther lives.
等到他为瓦坎达的命运而战时
And when he fights for the fate of Wakanda
我也会伴他左右
I will be right there beside him.
我也是
As will I.
我也加入
I'm in, too.
怎么了 你会需要全部的帮助
What? You're gonna need all the help you can get.
你们煽情够了没
Are you done?
够了没
可以让我和姆巴库大人单独谈谈吗
Could you give me and lord M'Baku a moment?
谢谢
Thank you.
我欠你个大人情
I owed you a great debt.
一命换一命
A life for a life.
我们两清了
Consider it paid.
请允许我母亲留下
Please allow my mother to stay here.
她不会有事的 我保证
No harm will come to her. I give you my word.
我还挺需要支军队的
You know, I could use an army as well.
当然了
I bet you could.
但不行
But no.
我不能让贾巴里人为你的使命送死
I will give no Jabari lives towards your cause.
这是我们的使命
It is our cause.
- 这是为了我们所有人 - 我们吗
- It is for all of us. - Oh, us'?
你是几世纪来第一个屈尊到此的国王
Us? You are the first king to come here in centuries,
现在还说什么"我们"
and now you speak of "Us"?
我无法代表先王们
I cannot speak for past kings.
但此刻 有敌人坐在王座上
But an enemy sits on the throne right now.
我们都清楚振金的威力
We both know the power of vibranium.
如果杀人魔头拿到了它
If Killmonger gains control of it,
你觉得他会来找谁
who do you think he will come for next?
我们不会
We will not
帮你的
help you.
一切就绪
Everything is on schedule.
探子都收到消息了吗
Have the spies been alerted?
是的 有些人抗拒我们的新任务
Yes. Some resistance to our new mission.
但伦敦 纽约
But the war dogs in London,New York
和香港的战士都就绪了
and Hong Kong are standing by.
我们先攻击那里
We'll strike there first.
其他人会想通的
The others will come around.
看啊
Look at this.
手持声波炮
A handheld Sonic Cannon,
足以抵挡一辆坦克
powerful enough to stop a tank...
金属探测器又探测不到
Untraceable by metal detectors.
而我们有数千支
And we got thousands of them.
世界会清楚地了解我们的本事
The world's gonna find out exactly who we are.
他没死
He lives.
尼贾达卡
N'jadaka!
你好啊
Wassup?
我还没认输呢
I never yielded!
你看到了 我也没死
And as you can see, I am not dead!
挑战已经结束了
All that challenge shit is over with!
我现在是国王了
I'm the king now!
让飞机升空 继续任务
Get those planes in the air! Carry out the mission!
- 苏睿 动手 - 收到
- Shuri, now. - Copy that.
走 快走 走啊 罗斯
Go, go, go! Come on, Ross!
瓦卡比 杀了这小丑
W'Kabi, man, kill this clown.
瓦卡比 挑战还没结束
W'Kabi, the challenge is not complete.
我们怎么办
What will we do?
边境部落
Border tribe!
你
You!
你的心里满是仇恨
Your heart is so full of hatred...
你不配做国王
You are not fit to be a king!
- 来啊 - 阿由 去帮国王
- Come on! - Ayo, the king!
盾
Shields!
瓦卡比 停下吧
W'Kabi, stop this!
马上停下
Stop this now!
不
No!
娜吉雅和我会靠这个控制王室飞船
Nakia and I will get control of the royal Talon with this.
那我做什么
So what do I do?
你得驾驶它
You'll have to fly it.
- 什么 - 你曾是优秀的飞行员
- What? - You were a great pilot.
别担心 我会教你的
Don't worry, I'll guide you through it.
就像开飞行摩托一样
It's just like riding a hoverbike.
什么 你们还有飞行摩托吗
What? You guys have hoverbikes?
娜吉雅 拿那个
Hey, Nakia, take that.
- 我不是护卫队的 - 穿上吧 那是盔甲
- I'm not a dora. - Just put it on, it's armor!
快来
Come!
祝你好运 罗斯特工
Good luck, Agent Ross!
我不知道该怎么办
Yeah, I don't know what I'm doing with this.
我们指望你了
We're counting on you.
瓦坎达万岁
Wakanda forever.
来啊
Come on!
上
Go, go!
遥控驾驶系统已启动
Remote piloting system activated.
天呐
My god.
我为你弄成美国式的了 上去吧
I made it American style for you. Get in.
好
All right.
太好了
Yes!
快走 别让武器离开瓦坎达境内
Go! We can't let those weapons get beyond Wakanda.
好 我去了
All right, I'm on it.
锁住
Lock!
压住他
Get him down!
拿项链
Get the necklace!
瓦坎达万岁
Wakanda forever!
苏睿 我看到它们了 怎么做
Okay, Shuri. I got 'em. What do I do?
击落啊 大天才
Shoot them down, genius!
好吧
All right.
放手一搏吧
Here goes nothing.
击落了
All right, got them.
该死
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
好啊
Nice!
苏睿
Shuri!
好啊 公主
What's up, Princess?
你永远不会成为真正的国王
You'll never be a true king.
哥哥
Brother!
苏睿
Shuri.
哥哥
Brother!
打开底层的火车
Turn on the train on the bottom track.
稳定器会让你的战服失效的
The stabilizers will deactivate your suit!
你就没有保护了
You won't have protection!
他也一样
Neither will he.
好
Okay!
我不需要战服也能杀了你
I don't need a suit to kill you.
你的统治结束了
Your reign is over!
你坐在这里 安全无忧
You sat up here, safe and protected.
你希望我们成为
You want to see us become
你如此仇视的那些人
just like the people you hate so much.
像他们那样逐个击破这个世界
Divide and conquer the land as they did!
不 我是学习了我的敌人
Nah, I learn from my enemies.
在他们的游戏里打败他们
Beat them at they own game.
你已经变成了他们
You have become them!
你会毁灭这个世界 包括瓦坎达
You will destroy the world, Wakanda included!
世界夺走了我的一切
The world took everything away from me!
我爱的一切
Everything I ever loved!
但我会跟世界扯平的
But I'm gonna make sure we're even.
我会找到每一个想要忠于你的人
I'm gonna track down anyone who would even think about being loyal to you!
然后把他们埋进黄土之下跟祖厉做邻居
And I'm gonna put they ass in the dirt right next to Zuri!
娜吉雅
Nakia!
- 你没事吧 - 我没事 你呢
- Are you all right? - I'm okay. You?
- 没事 - 我们走
- Yes. - Let's go.
苏睿 我甩掉了一个 但后面还追着俩
Shuri, I've lost one of them, but two are on my tail.
该死 那是什么
Shit. What the hell was that?
实验室遭受了袭击
The lab is under attack.
什么 哪里
What? Where?
取消全息图
Deactivating hologram.
罗斯 你得快跑
Ross, you have to get out of there, now!
我还有多久
How long have I got?
玻璃完整性为50%
Glass integrity is at 50%.
让我继续
Put me back in.
罗斯 罗斯
Ross! Ross!
投降吧
Surrender now!
给你们三秒放下武器
You have three seconds to lay down your weapon!
一
One!
二
Two!
亲眼见证贾巴里的威力吧
Witness the might of the Jabari firsthand!
玻璃完整性为15%
Glass integrity is at 15%.
- 武器严重失效 - 该死
- Critical weapons failure. - Shit!
苏睿 最后一辆货运飞船
Hey, Shuri! The last cargo ship
就要到边境了
is almost at the border...
但他们拿某种缆线困住了我
But they got me trapped with some kind of cables.
交叉胳膊
Make an x with your arms!
音波过载已启动
Sonic overload initiated.
展开
Now break it!
系统正在重启 五
System rebooting in five...
三 四
Four, three...
二 一
Two, one.
系统已重启
System rebooted.
好啊 成功了
Yes! We did it!
太好了 快走吧
Great! Now get out of there!
冲
Charge!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
你会杀了我吗 亲爱的
Would you kill me, my love?
为了瓦坎达
For Wakanda?
毫无疑问
Without question!
你完蛋了 堂哥
This is it for you, cousin.
好厉害的一招
Hell of a move!
我爸说
My pop said
瓦坎达是他见过的最美的景色
Wakanda was the most beautiful thing he ever seen.
他答应过有一天会带我来见识见识
He promised he was gonna show it to me one day.
你相信吗
You believe that?
一个奥克兰孩子 却相信一个童话
Kid from Oakland, running around believing in fairy tales.
好美啊
It's beautiful.
或许我们还能治好你
Maybe we can still heal you.
为什么
Why?
好让你把我关起来吗
So you can just lock me up?
不
Nah.
把我葬在海里
Just bury me in the ocean...
陪伴那些为自由而跳船的先祖
With my ancestors that jumped from the ships.
因为他们知道 为奴不如赴死
'Cause they knew death was better than bondage.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你救了我
You saved me.
你救了我的家族
You saved my family.
我们的国家
Our nation.
不用谢我
There's nothing to thank me for.
我们的职责就是…
It is our duty to...
我的职责就是为我所爱而战
It was my duty to fight for what I love.
我本该…
I should've...
你不能怪我 我差点就死了
You can't blame me, I almost died.
留下吧
Stay.
我知道还有个办法能让你实现使命
I think I know a way you can still fulfill your calling.
求你留下吧
Please stay.
他突破了 突破了
Oh, he moves it! He moves it!
- 那人是谁 - 篮下禁区
- Who man is that? - Bucket!
轻松
Easy.
你说要第一次带我来加州的时候
When you said you would take me to California for the first time...
我以为你是指去柯契拉音乐节
I thought you meant Coachella...
或是迪士尼乐园
Or Disneyland.
为什么来这里
Why here?
这是我们父亲杀了叔叔的地方
This is where our father killed our uncle.
警告  禁止入内
他们要拆楼
They're tearing it down.
很好
Good.
他们不是要拆楼
They are not tearing it down.
我买下了这栋楼
I bought this building.
还有那栋楼
And that building.
还有那边那栋
And that one over there.
这里将成为第一座瓦坎达国际外联中心
This will be the first Wakandan international outreach center.
娜吉雅负责社会交流工作
Nakia will oversee the social outreach.
你领导科技信息交流
And you will spearhead the science and information exchange.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
那是什么玩意
Man, what the hell is that?
像是布加迪宇宙飞船
That's like a Bugatti spaceship!
兄弟 它凭空就冒出来了 你们看见没
Bro, it came out of nowhere. Did y'all see that?
什么
What?
好好看看 兄弟
Check it out, bro.
我们可以坐这个回家
We can take this back to the house.
搭它去学校
Pull up to school in this.
我们可以把它拆了卖掉
Look, we can break it apart. We can sell it.
在易趣网上卖
On ebay.
卖价是一百万一个零部件
Everybody get, like, a million a piece.
我可不建议你们那么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you guys.
- 你从哪来 - 瓦坎达
- Where you come from? - From Wakanda.
瓦坎达是什么
What is a Wakanda?
嘿
Hey, yo!
那是你的吗
This yours?
你…
Who...
你是谁
Who are you?
黑 豹
联 合 国
奥地利维也纳
我是特查拉国王
My name is King T'Challa...
特查卡国王之子
Son of King T'Chaka.
我是瓦坎达的最高统治者
I am the sovereign ruler of the nation of Wakanda.
我们史上第一次
And for the first time in our history...
将与外界共享我们的
we will be sharing our knowledge and resources...
知识和资源
with the outside world.
瓦坎达将不再只从隐蔽处窥探
Wakanda will no longer watch from the shadows.
我们不会
We cannot.
也不能再如此
We must not.
我们会尽力成为榜样
We will work to be an example
让世人看到 地球上的人和国家
of how we as brothers and sisters on this earth
应亲如兄弟姐妹
should treat each other.
现在 甚于以往
Now, more than ever...
分裂的幻觉威胁着我们的存在
The illusions of division threaten our very existence.
我们都知道真相
We all know the truth.
我们的共同点多于不同之处
More connects us than separates us.
但面对危机时
But in times of crisis
智者建桥
the wise build Bridges
愚者筑墙
while the foolish build barriers.
我们必须想方法
We must find a way
彼此照应
to look after one another
团结一致 情同一家
as if we were one, single tribe.
恕我直言 国王特查拉
With all due respect, King T'Challa,
一个农业国家能为世界提供什么
what can a nation of farmers have to offer the rest of the world?
你们又跟他玩了吗
Are you playing around with that man again?
- 没有 - 你们又在逗他
- No. - You're teasing him again.
- 别吵醒他 让他休息 - 我没吵他
- Don't wake him. He must rest. - No, I'm not.
我没有
No, I'm not.
塔博 你有
Thabo, you're doing that.
他有 他撒谎
He's doing it. He's lying.
没有 他在休息
No, he's resting.
去吧
Go, go!
白狼
White wolf!
别闹了
Stop that!
白狼
White wolf!
早上好 巴恩斯中士
Good morning, Sergeant Barnes.
喊我巴基就行
Bucky.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
很好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧
Come.
你还有很多要学呢
Much more for you to learn.
黑豹将在《复仇者联盟3：无限战争》中回归